AYANLEYE S. OLUWATOYIN

JUNIOR PENETRATION TESTER

Summary

A young professional starting out in the Cybersecurity field, skilled in scripting, web application penetration testing, network security, firmware development, and embedded application development. Currently working on Bug Bounties, open-source web application code review and testing, and developing an automation script for carrying out reconnaissance, vulnerability discovery and testing that would otherwise be done manually. Continuously learning using platforms such as HackTheBox, TryHackMe, PawnTillDawn, and VulnHub. Also preparing for related Certification Exams.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS: Python, C, C++, Bash, Yocto **TOOLSETS AND OS:** Linux, Windows, GitHub, Git, Wireshark, Nessus, VMware, Metasploit, Burpsuite, Docker

HARDWARE: Reading Schematics, Circuit Prototyping, Referencing HW datasheets, Raspberry Pi, Arduino

TECHNICAL SKILLS: Web Application Penetration Testing, Network Vulnerability Testing, Bug Bounty

Projects

Automated Network Domain Scanning Tool

- Custom Automated Scanner for Web and Networks. It works using modules and plugins to each module to extend functionality.
- It automates common manual Penetration Testing practices and is continuously developed using publicly available information and personal experiences.
- Current modules include Domain Recon for Bug Bounties and Network Automated Scanning and Exploit Suggestion.
- The project is still in early stages and as such the repo is still private.

Pentesting Environment Setup Tool

- Bash script for one line install of most penetration testing tools for Debian based Linux Distributions e.g. AWS VPS and Raspberry Pi 4 (64-bit)

Visis Glasses

- Prototype product for Vinsighte Technology, which is their product for the visually impaired

Vixen Modular Pet

- Created a modular robotic pet with obstacle detection and 2 behaviors, based on the TIVA LaunchPad

Ardupilot Based Drone

- Constructed a drone using the ardupilot flight controller and adding a master microcontroller for autonomous control

Employment

M4xH3dr00m

Team Member

July 2021 to Present

Nigeria

- Won CyberTalents Nationals CTF and America Business Council CTF
- Discovered and found a solution to Laravel Illuminate Validation RCE via an upload vulnerability

Linux Professional Institute Innovation Hub

Appleton Road, Ibadan Mar. 2020 to Dec. 2020

- Trained high school students on the basics of programming and robotics
- Introduced University students to cybersecurity and gave introductory training and materials
- I served as technical support for hosted events

Vinsighte

Appleton Road, University of Ibadan, Ibadan

Embedded Software Developer

Oct. 2019 to Apr. 2020

Feb. 2017 to Present

- Successfully developed the prototype for reading glasses for the visually impaired

Education

University of Ibadan

B.Sc Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2022

The International School Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago-Iwoye Sept. 2012 to July 2016

Trinity International College, Ofada Sept. 2010 to July 2012

Hacking Platforms

TryHackMe

NullCell - tryhackme.com/p/NullCell

TryHackMe is a free online platform for learning cyber security, using hands-on exercises and labs, all through your browser

HackTheBox

NullCell - hackthebox.eu/home/users/profile/462764

Hack The Box is a massive, online cyber security training platform, allowing individuals, companies, universities and all kinds of organizations around the world to level up their hacking skills

PwnTillDawn

NullCell - online.pwntilldawn.com/Achievements/2087

PwnTillDawn Online Battlefield is wizlynx group's vision of the next-generation offensive security & Penetration testing lab but also capture-the-flag competition

Volunteering

Google Developer Student Club - University of Ibadan \cdot cybersecurity Lead Ibadan, Nigeria

Present

Trained fellow students who want to get into the field of Cybersecurity

IEEE-UISB · Embedded Team Lead

University of Ibadan

Worked on maze solving RC cars

Awards

 $Cyber\ Talents\cdot {\it Cyber\ Talents\ Nationals\ CTF\ -\ Nigeria\ 1st\ Place}$

Sept. 2021

Sept. 2021

- Cyber Talents' Annual CTF National for Nigeria to qualify for Africa and Middle-East Challenge

American Business Council · American Business Council Cybersecurity CTF 2nd Place

- A CTF hosted by The American Business Council Nigeria for Cybersecurity Professionals

CampusLabs with US Embassy · Hackathon Winner

Apr. 2019

A disability hackathon to find solutions to help people with various kinds of disabilities. My solution proposed a design for an autom

Hult Prize Foundation · Hult Prize

Oct. 2018

- Hult prize UI for creating jobs for 10,000 people withing the next 10 years.